<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blogging | The Tipter Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://tipter.github.com/blog/categories/blogging/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tipter.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-08T19:29:52+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://tipter.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[The Tipter Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Does the world needs another travel web app?]]></title>
    <link href="http://tipter.github.com/blog/2013/05/08/does-the-world-needs-another-travel-web-app/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-08T15:01:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://tipter.github.com/blog/2013/05/08/does-the-world-needs-another-travel-web-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left" src="/images/pileofpaper.jpg" width="400" height="400" title="image" alt="images"></p>

<p>Well, as a matter of fact, it does. And you can tell it does from the sheer helplessness one might feel when planning a trip. At least, that's the way we always felt when planning our trips. So, we thought of a solution. It is called Tipter.</p>

<p>How do you plan your trip? There are always so many constraints.... it could be time, a tight budget, a specific season, the age of the participants, and a lot of other factors. It’s was always a painful and time consuming task, unless you’ve got unlimited budget, all the time in the world, and you are travelling with your identical twin.... as for rest of us, we could use a little help.</p>

<p>Of course, you can always buy a travel guide, like in the good old days before the Internet changed our lives. Or you can start by using Google or Bing to try to find some bits and pieces of information, hoping the world wide web will be kind enough to answer all your questions such as where to go when you travel to the south of France for three weeks, or what to do with two kids in Thailand. But from our personal and sometimes painful experience, you usually won’t get the right answers.</p>

<p>The problem, we have come to realize, is most online sources are focused on flights, hotels, and restaurants. The web won’t give you the big picture, or the specific information, which makes the difference between a great trip and an okay, or even frustrating one. You might find a nice hotel or a good restaurant, but that’s the easy part. What you need is the combined wisdom of other travelers like you, who have been there and done that, and can tell you all about it.
How can Tipter help you plan your trip?</p>

<p>Tipter is a sophisticated social network of travelers like you, who share with the world their personal experience and traveling tips. Tipter holds information from people who have been where you want to visit, “asking” them about where to go, how much time to spend at each location, what is there to do, where are the cool places to hang around, the great local restaurant no one ever heard about, and much more. This process, which can be tedious and time consuming when done on your own, becomes fun and easy with Tipter. It informs you of all there it is to do, and helps you sort between the places you want to spend your time on and the places you don’t.</p>

<p>And when you come back from the trip, you are filled with great memories, tips, and recommendations. You can share your own “inside info” with friends and family, with the people who helped you, and with the whole world. Or, you could blog it while on the road, sending real time updates, and keeping in touch from everywhere in the world. And so the motion of tips and tells continue, other people will use your advice as a basis for their next trip and share their knowledge afterward. What you get in the end is the best, most updated and helpful travel guide for the 21st century. What you get is Tipter.   </p>

<p>So yes, we do think the world needs another travel web app; it needs the right one, and we devoted the last year to building and improving it. And today, we are more than pleased to let you know it is taking its first baby steps. Not all features are there yet, but we’re improving it on a daily basis. You’ll probably find tons of bugs and we have a long way to go, but we’ll get there - and then, progress even further. This is something we have invested a lot of thinking in, so we can try to solve the above questions - for ourselves and for you. Come on aboard and give it a go.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
